# Nicole Aldurien

Software Engineer

Atlanta, GA | nicole.aldurien@gmail.com

nicole-aldurien.surge.sh | github.com/nicolealdurien | linkedin.com/in/nicolealdurien

Creative software engineer with the ability to pick up new languages and technologies as needed. Prior to changing careers, I worked as a certified medical laboratory scientist for Emory University Hospital, where I conducted immunohematological testing to ensure safe administration of blood and bone marrow transplants to inpatients and outpatients at Georgia's largest academic medical center.

### **Software Development Skills**

 Debugging, JavaScript, Python, Node.js, React, Express, Redux, RESTful API, PostgreSQL, Sequelize, Bootstrap, Flexbox, AWS, React Native, HTML, CSS

#### **Education**

DigitalCrafts | Certificate in Software Engineering | Atlanta, GA

February 2021 - present

• Software engineering training program covering full-stack development including (but not limited to) JavaScript and Python, with an emphasis on cutting-edge frameworks like React/Redux and server-side technologies including Node.js, Express, and PostgreSQL.

Texas State University | B.S. in Clinical Laboratory Science | San Marcos, TX | STEM GPA: 4.0

degree conferred August 2014

## **Software Development Portfolio**

wasteNOT | wastenotorg.herokuapp.com | github.com/nicolealdurien/wasteNOT

April 2021

- Member of a 3-person development team on a distributed, modified-follow-the-sun schedule (due to one team member's
  family commitments), building a website that allows a theoretical charity to facilitate donation of excess unsold food from
  restaurants to food banks and soup kitchens.
- Primary responsibilities included implementing a fully mobile-responsive layout, schema design for user, admin, donation, and food bank tables in Postgres, creating user registration functionality with password encryption, and creating food bank information page and location page.
- Built with Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, Mustache, HTML, and CSS.

Catch Up Over Coffee | catch-up-over-coffee.surge.sh | github.com/nicolealdurien/catch-up-over-coffee

March 2021

- Member of a 4-person development team building a one-stop website where users can start their morning by catching up on news, viewing the latest stock market quotes, checking out local weather, and more.
- Primary responsibilities included proper project scoping and timeboxing for the team, implementing a fully mobileresponsive layout, developing news page functionality including API consumption/duplicate story removal/filtering stories by
  topic and source, and creation of in-house JSON documents to pull from for sections of the site without good public APIs.
- Built with Javascript, HTML, and CSS; consumes multiple RESTful APIs.

#### **Professional Work Experience**

Emory University Hospital | Medical Technologist II | Atlanta, GA

April 2016 – December 2020

• Performed compatibility testing on patients, donor blood, and bone marrow transplant products to ensure safe transfusions at a 600-bed hospital. Collaborated daily with staff at the Red Cross and other area hospitals to best serve the region's patients.

Reproductive Biology Associates | Medical Technologist/Andrologist | Atlanta, GA

September 2014 - April 2016

Performed andrological and endocrine testing for potential IVF patients. Guided patients seeking donor sperm through the
process of selecting a bank, ordering, and shipping vials to us. Maintained FDA-compliant records for frozen specimens.